Bastards!
この…
Lieutenant Marito!
鞠戸大尉
All units, scatter!
全機散開
Well, that didn't work.
だめか
Since he uses lightning for both
defense and offense,
攻撃も雷撃で行うなら
その転換の間　隙が生まれると思ったが
I thought there might be an opening
...when he switches between them, but...
It looks like it'll be more complicated than that.
やはり　そう甘くはないようですね
だとすれば　ほかに打てる手は
So what are our options?
Lieutenant Marito!
鞠戸大尉
Message from the Deucalion!
デューカリオンにより伝達　撤退命令が司令部から出ました
HQ is ordering us to pull back.
Pull back?!
撤退？　全軍が？
All forces?
Dales Platoon and Orlov Platoon
should have gotten the same order.
デイルズ小隊　オルロフ小隊もすでに命令を受けているはずです
Except...
ただ…
Except what?
ただ何だ
Pull back! Pull back!
引け　引け
Dales 22!
デイルズ22
Where's the enemy?
敵は　敵はどこだ
Where is he?
Captain!
隊長
The invisible Cataphract we
couldn't destroy is over there.
さっき倒し損ねた透明カタフラクトが向こうに
Shit.
くそ
Clydesdale Leader to Orlov Leader.
クライスデールリーダーよりオルロフリーダー
Can you hear me?
聞こえるか　撤退だ
Pull back!
This is Orlov Leader.
こちら　オルロフリーダー
We can't...
無理だ
I'm...
こちらは…
the last one...
もう　自分しか残っていない
A lightning one,
雷撃と透明
an invisible one...
それに　もう一機
and a third one too?
Tell them to carry on.
そのまま続けろと伝えろ
包囲し　殲滅だ
Surround and annihilate them.
仰せの通りに
As you wish.
Princess Asseylum!
アセイラム姫　一体…
What is this?
I've done all I can.
手は尽くした
All we can do is pray now.
これが限界だ
Forgive me, Slaine.
すまぬ　スレイン
But...
そんな…
kimi no te ga hirogeta nani mo nai sora yo
Your hands spread out the vast and empty sky
君の手が広げた　何もない空よ
rikutsu no umi dake no kai wo asobeba
when you played with what the sea of reason would give
理屈の海だけの　解を遊べば
hodoite wa koboreta tagai no namida
Our tears welled up and fell
ほどいては溢れた　お互いのナミダ
kouka shita kotoba uso kimagure
Words, lies, and whim down from orbit
降下した言葉・嘘・キマグレ
soul art
Soul art
soul・art　リズムを奏でて
rhythm kanadete
We play a song now
aizu wo ringu ni tsunagu
and connect the signs to a ring
合図をリングに繋ぐ
形だけのシステムと
katachi dake no system to
A system of pure shape
katami dake no majinai mo
A magic spell without power
形見だけの呪いも
toubounin no hajirai on
The sound of shy fugitives
逃亡人の恥じらい音
想像Drive　CarryOn　意地なTIRE
souzou drive carryon iji na tire
Carry on imagining, don't give up
誤解あるドアに　ゼロが眠りかけた
gokai aru doa ni zero ga nemurikaketa
We're running out of false doors
tokei daita hito to tenshi
Men and angels embrace the passage of time
時計抱いた人と天使
towa ni aku doorutachi
They are dolls who gave up on eternity,
永久に飽くドール達
mata onaji kaze ni mogaite
fighting against this recurring fever
また同じ風邪に　モガいて
Dales 11!
デイルズ11
クライスデールリーダー？
Clydesdale Leader!
Kaizuka Junior!
界塚弟
撤退してください
Pull back!
The smokescreen should give us a degree of cover.
多少は煙幕で敵の視界が遮られているはずです
Go!
行け
りょ…了解
R-Roger!
そして　この煙は攻撃にも利用できる
We can also use the smoke to attack.
Found you.
捉えた
右だ　逃げろ
On your right! Evade fire!
Mustang Leader!
マスタングリーダー
What's happening, Kaizuka?
どうした　界塚
雷撃の足止めは任せたはずだぞ
I thought you were gonna keep the lightning one busy!
I'm sorry!
すみません
It suddenly shifted its attention to you.
そちらに攻撃を集中するかのように　急に矛先を変えて
くそ
Are we surrounded?
囲まれた
みたいです
I think so.
デューカリオン
The Deucalion?
Damage report!
被害は？
Nothing serious!
大丈夫です　放電できてます
We're discharging it!
Set the ship down and extract all our Cataphracts.
着陸し　全カタフラクトを救出
On the battlefield?
ここにですか
The enemy is right there!
敵のど真ん中です
Put the ship down!
着陸する
KCAS, ten knots.
KCAS 10ノット
落としすぎだ　追い風も強い
We're going down too fast.
Don't forget the tail wind!
It's fine!
大丈夫　アルドノアドライブ効いてます
The Aldnoah Drive can handle it!
Send all power to the antigravity device!
反重力デバイス最大　バーティカルスピード1200フィートパーセカンド
Vertical speed to 1,200 feet per second!
Get on the ship!
乗り込むぞ
デイルズ小隊を誘導　急げ
Grab Dales Platoon and hurry!
下部ハッチを開け
Open the bow doors!
Retrieve all our Cataphracts!
全カタフラクトを回収する
Nine o'clock!
九時の方向
Enemy Cataphract is approaching!
敵カタフラクト　接近
Fire the main guns!
主砲発射
全カタフラクト　回収完了
All Cataphracts extracted.
離脱する
Take off!
何だ
What's that?
後方に敵カタフラクト　さっき倒したのと同じタイプっス
Another Cataphract on our stern!
Same type as the one we destroyed!
増援？
Reinforcements?
二時の方向にも
Another at two o'clock!
増援ではありません　これは…
They can't be reinforcements.
They're...
敵影　12
Twelve enemy contacts... Sixteen... Twenty-four...
16…　24…
どんどん増えています
It keeps climbing!
分身能力？
Can it replicate itself?
Full ahead!
両舷いっぱい
Die!
この…
Weather radar, Doppler radar, both offline!
ウェザーレーダー　ドップラーレーダー　機能停止
Shit!
くそ　透明の矢の攻撃で　放電索にダメージが
The invisible bastard must have damaged our discharge equipment with his attack!
All comm links are dead!
無線もだめっス
GPS link lost!
GPS表示消失　二次レーダーもアウトだ
2D radar is dead too!
But...
そんな…
Stay calm!
落ち着きなさい　上昇を続けて
Keep ascending!
Roger.
はい
そうか　トロイヤード卿に従う気になったというのだな
I see.
So I could convince you of the wisdom of following Count Troyard.
Yes.
はい
I shall let him know at once.
早速話は通しておく
There is one thing I would ask of you in return.
加えてお願いがございます
What is it?
何だ
Might I be granted an audience with Princess Asseylum?
アセイラム姫に拝謁は叶いますでしょうか
What?
何　姫に直接
An audience with Her Highness?
Yes. And if possible, with Count Troyard as well.
はい　可能であればトロイヤード卿にも
That isn't as easy as it seems.
それはなかなか難しいが
However, I shall attempt to see your wish accommodated.
まあ　便宜がはかれるよう努力はする
You will be indebted to me, of course.
それなりの見返りは必要になると思うがな
I understand.
心得ております
しかし敗北は人を育てるというが　貴公もなかなかだな
I suppose the saying goes that defeat makes you stronger, but you're exemplary.
You are attempting to be on good terms not only with Count Troyard but also with Princess Asseylum.
トロイヤード卿のみならず　姫君にも覚えをいただければ何よりの力
However, don't make your ambitions so obvious.
だが　あまり野心を表に出すなよ
Someone might exploit them.
足を掬われる可能性もあるぞ
はあ…
Princess Asseylum is an impostor.
アセイラム姫は偽物です
I'm going into space.
宇宙にあがる　シャトルの用意を
Prepare a shuttle.
戦勝おめでとうございます　スレイン様
Congratulations on your victory,
Sir Slaine.
Letting the enemy escape is hardly cause for congratulations.
あまり喜べないな　みすみす敵を逃がしては
We did, however, accomplish our primary objective of securing territory.
領地の確保という目的は果たしたのです
A fine victory, I would think.
十分成功ではありませんか
これでまた忠誠を誓う騎士たちが増えることでしょう
No doubt the ranks of those loyal to you will swell.
We shouldn't let our guard down.
油断は禁物だ
Nothing is less reliable than a knight's pledge of fealty.
騎士の忠誠という言葉ほど　当てに出来ないものはない
重々承知しております
I understand entirely.
Now, how should I answer
Count Barouhcruz's request?
それから　バルークルス様よりご依頼の件ですが
いかがいたしましょう
Let him have his wish.
構わん
My lord?
マズゥールカと言ったか
Mazuurek, right?
He can meet the princess if he so desires.
姫に会いたいというなら　会わせればいい
She will be only too happy to help us grow in power.
姫も喜んでこちらの勢力を増やす役割を果たしてくれる
For now, at least.
少なくとも　今は
だめだ　応急で復旧できるレベルじゃない
No good.
This isn't something we can fix with duct tape.
Seriously?
そんな…
ノクトビジョンもやられてるし　有視界飛行じゃとても…
Night vision's out as well,
so I can't even fly by eye!
故障は　センサー系ですか
What isn't working? The sensors?
どうして分かったのです　界塚少尉
How did you know that, Lieutenant Kaizuka?
すぐ分かります
It couldn't be much else.
The ship has been meandering.
機体が微妙にですが　ずっと流れている
エンジン周りの不備はこの船では考えづらいし
It's hard to imagine there could be
any defects in the engine.
だとすれば…
So...
E-Enough of that! Just help us out!
とにかく助けて　いろいろとまずくて
Everything's going wrong!
もう少し高度を下げたほうがいい　敵のレーダーにかからない程度に
I suggest lowering our altitude somewhat.
If we fly low enough, enemy radar won't detect us.
でも　高度計もGPWSも死んでるから　低すぎると怖い
I'm too nervous to go any lower with the altimeter and GPWS both dead.
I can determine how high we are.
把握できてる　今9200
We're currently at 9,200.
そこまで見えるんだ
You can see all that?
VORも捕まえられますか
Can you also pick up VOR stations?
ええ
Yes.
至近の二点を掴めたら頼む　ラジアルを割り出す
When you can read both signals, let me know.
I'll calculate our radial.
はい
Got it.
進路は？　110のつもりだけど
What's our heading? I was trying to put us on 110.
大体正解
You're pretty much on track.
3度のオフセットを2分　あとは戻してキープ
Offset yourself by three degrees for
two minutes, and then straighten out.
まずいな　質の悪い気流にはまったか
This isn't good. Are we caught in some nasty turbulence?
続きそうです　念のため速度を
Seems it's a long patch.
Just in case, slow—
任せて
Leave it to me.
このくらいなら　前にも
This is easy. I've done it before.
だね
You're right.
ここから先は経験のほうが物を言いそうだ
I guess experience will be the most important thing from here on out.
LLGがキャッチできたら教える
If I catch an LLG, I'll let you know.
はい
Right!
ありがとう
Thank you.
こちらのほうこそ　先程は
Actually, we should be thanking you for earlier.
鞠戸大尉が驚いていました　ずいぶん無茶をすると
Lieutenant Marito was surprised you'd do something so crazy.
「あなたには言われたくない」
Tell him he's the last person who can talk.
そう伝えてください
そうですか
I see.
建国の準備は着々と進んでいるのですね
So the preparations for the founding are proceeding smoothly?
はい
Yes.
楽しみにしてるのですよ　新しい王国
I'm so excited.
A new kingdom.
あなたの故郷に行けることも
And I can visit your homeworld, too.
粗野な者たちの住まう星です
It's a planet of apes, not men.
故郷と言えるような　安らげるところでも
It may be where I am from, but it is hardly home—
いえ　もとより僕にそういう場所はありません
or rather, I suppose I never had a home.
それは私も同じです
We're the same in that regard.
ヴァースも　王族という地位も
Neither Vers nor my noble rank offer me any peace.
私にとって安住の場所ではありません
スレイン
Slaine.
あなたと共にいられる場所が　私にとっては…
Anywhere I may be together with you,
more than anywhere else,
どこよりも…
is my home.
光栄に　存じます
You honor me.
では　また改めまして
I shall return later, then.
スレイン　晩餐の用意は整っているのですよ
Wait, Slaine. I've had dinner prepared.
あいにくですが　まだ所用を控えております
Unfortunately, I still have many pressing matters to attend to.
お許してください
Please forgive me.
伊奈帆
Inaho—
Oh, Inko.
韻子
どうしたの
What's up?
あ…あのね　昨日ニーナすごく助かったって　喜んでたよ
U-Um, you really helped Nina yesterday. She was super happy.
ああ　うん
Oh. Sure.
U-Um...
あ…あの　どうかした
Is something wrong?
What do you mean?
何が
What do you mean, what?
何がって
何でもないけど
Never mind.
どう思います？　敵が連携を取ってきたことは
What do you make of the enemy's coordinated attacks?
単に向こうがプライドを捨てざるを得ないほど追い詰められたか
If they're simply so backed into a corner that they're forced to throw away their pride,
その結果ということなら　さして恐れることもないでしょうがね
then we probably have nothing to be afraid of.
やはり　あの宣言が関係しているということでしょうか
So you think it has something
to do with the announcement?
アセイラム姫の背後にいるトロイヤードとかいう軌道騎士
That Orbital Knight named Slaine Troyard who's always lurking behind Princess Asseylum...
界塚弟も一目置いてる相手だとか
He's even beaten Kaizuka Junior.
If everything that's happened is part of that boy's plan,
その相手が　すべて計画的にことを動かしているのだとすれば
こちらも　ただ物量で対抗するというような安易な策では
then this isn't something we
can win with numbers alone.
Come in.
どうぞ
祭陽上等兵　入ります
Private Matsuribi, sir and madams.
本部より　通達です
I have a message from HQ.
援軍の依頼ですか
A request for reinforcements?
"Launch an all-out attack
to reclaim our captured territory."
占領された地域に総攻撃をかけ　奪還せよ
物量で攻めろと
We're throwing sheer numbers at them?
そういうことです
That's the long and short of it.
その後　お加減はいかがですか
And how have you fared since?
ええ　体調はすっかり
Physically, I feel fine.
ただ　記憶の方は
However, my memory is still rather hazy.
まだ　少しぼんやりしていて
無理もありません
That is hardly surprising.
お目覚めになられたこと自体が　奇跡なのです
The very fact that you regained consciousness was nothing short of a miracle.
あまり…
Please...
あまり　無理に思い出さなくとも
Please do not force yourself to remember.
ありがとう　スレイン
Thank you, Slaine.
今日はこの辺りで失礼します
I'm afraid I must take my leave now.
ゆっくり休んでください
Please get some rest.
ええ
I will.
また来ます　姫様を
I shall return. Please look after Her Highness.
Excuse me, Sir Slaine...
あの　スレイン様
聞きたいことの見当はつきます
I can guess what you wish to ask about.
The proclamation, yes? Taking me as her husband
and founding a new kingdom...
宣言のことですね
僕を夫に迎え　王国を作る
レムリナ姫によって発せられたあの宣言…
That proclamation issued by Princess Lemrina
すべては　僕の心の弱さが招いたことです
was born from the weakness in my heart.
アセイラム姫は必ず目覚める
I tried to hold on to my faith that Princess Asseylum would awaken some day,
そう信じようとしながら　結局信じきれず
どこかで　諦めてしまっていた
but I suppose I must have given up
somewhere deep down.
けれど　その僕の愚かをたしなめるように　奇跡は起こりました
But then a miracle took place,
as if to reprimand me for being such a fool.
状況が大きく変わってしまった今
With the situation having changed so drastically,
僕が考えなければならないことは　いかに姫様を幸せに出来るか
the one thing I must focus on now
is how I can make Her Highness happy.
ただ　それだけです
I can spare a thought for nothing else.
でも　レムリナ様は
But what of Princess Lemrina?
彼女の求めているものは何か　僕には分かります
I understand what she is looking for.
多分　彼女と僕は同じものを　同じ安住の地を求めている
She likely seeks the same thing I do—
a place where she can find solace.
だけど　それは決して共には手に入れられぬもの
But that is something that
neither of us will ever obtain.
まだすべてをお話するわけにはいきません
We cannot tell her everything yet.
しかし　自分のやっていることを軽蔑されようと 罵られようと
It may be that she hates herself
for what she's doing right now,
別に構わないと思っています
but that does not concern me.
皮肉ですね
It's ironic.
あれほど姫様のお目覚めを待ち望んでいたのに
I had waited with such hope
for Her Highness to awaken.
今は　記憶が戻らないことを望んでいる
But now, my greatest hope
is that her memory never returns.
此度は私が信を置くトロイヤード卿に仕えるという意思を固められたとのこと
I am overjoyed to see your newfound resolve to serve my trusted Count Troyard.
まこと欣喜に絶えません
恐れ多きことにございます
Your Highness is too kind.
誠心誠意　アセイラム姫殿下
I am fully prepared to serve both Your Highness
and Count Troyard with wholehearted devotion.
そしてトロイヤード様にお仕えする覚悟でございます
一度は地球にて幽閉の身となりながら　ヴァースの未来のため
I too was touched by Count Mazuurek's drive
as he swore to rise up once again for the sake of Vers' future
今一度立ち上がろうと誓ったマズゥールカ卿の志に
私も心を打たれました
even as he was held prisoner on Earth.
恐れながら　姫殿下
Begging Your Highness' pardon...
姫殿下も地球にて同様な辛酸を味わわれたと伺っておりますが
I am given to understand that you once underwent similar hardships on Earth.
左様のこともありました
Yes, one could say that.
地球人は　その　粗野な者たちばかり
Terrans are all... so vulgar.
親しくなれたものは　一人もおりませんでしたか
There was no one that Your Highness grew close to?
親しくなど　まさか
Close to? I think not.
地球人の相手はすべて侍女に任せておりましたから
I left all interaction with Terrans to my handmaiden.
あのような者たちと　一度は和睦を考えたこともありましたが
I once entertained the notion
of reconciling with those people,
愚かであったと　今は思います
but now I see what a fool I was.
なぜスレインがいないのです？このような時に
Why is Slaine not here now, of all times?
スレイン様は新たな作戦の準備のために奔走しておりまして
Lord Slaine has been preoccupied with preparations for the new operation.
前にもそれは聞きました
He said as much earlier.
近頃は　城にこもっていることが多すぎます
He has been locking himself
in his castle far too often lately.
こちらではできぬことなのですか
Whatever he is doing,
can he not do it here?
大事な資料などもあることかと
I am told that precious resources are involved.
だったら　私が行きます
Then I shall go to him.
That would be...
それは…
私が　揚陸城に移ります
I shall go over to the Landing Castle!
姫様
Your Highness!
大丈夫ですか　姫様
Are you unharmed, Your Highness?
失礼します
Forgive me.
何時に　なったら…
How long will it be...
Tell me, how long will it be...
ね　何時になったら…
お部屋までお送りします
I shall see you to your room, Your Highness.
お待たせしました
Please pardon the delay, Count Mazuurek.
マズゥールカ伯爵
I will show you to the parlor.
応接室へ　ご案内します
身元の確認は終わったようですね
You've finished checking my credentials, I take it.
大変失礼を
I apologize for our discourtesy.
Not at all. The fault is entirely mine.
いえ　こちらこそとんだ失態
I was in quite the predicament when my ship broke down.
よもや船が故障するとは
お城が近くて　助かりました
How fortunate for me that
you should be in the vicinity.
そうですか　トロイヤード卿はまだ月面基地に
Oh, I see... Count Troyard is still at the moon base.
Yes. I regret to say that you have missed him.
はい　あいにくと行き違いで
ハークライト様が今　こちらに向かわれています
Master Harklight is on his way as we speak.
ヤツの不在を確認の上で仕掛けた
I made my move as soon as I was certain that he would not be here.
トロイヤードはこの城と月面基地を　必要以上に往復している
Troyard is traveling between here and the moon base more than he should need to.
姫の居場所は　あるいは…
That makes it clear where Her Highness must be.
こちらでお待ちください
Please wait here.
地球の花ですか
Are these Terran flowers?
Yes.
はい
随分と雰囲気が変わりましたね　この城も
This castle has undergone quite the transformation.
御存知なのですか
You can tell?
前の城主とは知り合いでした
I was an acquaintance of its former lord.
地球のものなど雑菌が付くと毛嫌いするような方でしたから
He detested all things Terran,
fearing that they harbored microorganisms.
その心配はございません
You need not worry.
地球で花なら何度も…
Flowers on Earth are perfectly safe—
地球に行かれたことが
Oh, you have been to Earth, then?
N-No. I'm simply relaying what I've heard.
い…いいえ　話しに聞いただけです
アセイラム殿下にはお付きの者がいたと聞いてますが
I heard Princess Asseylum had an attendant, but...
まさか…
No. I mean...
いえ　その…
姫様は地球へはお一人で
Her Highness went to Earth without me!
誰も　地球での話とは言ってません
I wasn't referring to Earth.
し…失礼します
I-I must be going!
本当に行ったことはありませんか
You truly have not been there?
地球でのことは知りませんか
Do you know of what took place on Earth?
界塚伊奈帆という少年のことは
What about a boy named Kaizuka Inaho?
何時になったら…
How long will it be?
ね　お姉様
Tell me, Sister...
何時になったら…
How long will it be before you
release your grip on his feelings?
解放してくださるの　あの人の気持ちを
私にですか
For me?
Yes. He said that he wanted me to give it to you.
はい
あの　姫様にお渡ししていただきたいと
地球のことを知ってる姫様に
To the princess who knew about Earth.
こ…これは
This amulet...
姫様
Your Highness!
私…
I...
私は…
本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流，禁止用于商业用途
更多中日双语字幕，尽在 i.kamigami.org 和微博 @诸神字幕组
日听:ikoko&Archer  翻译:mam&郝郝
校对:安少&zwx  时间轴:Foyzi  压制:河蟹
僕たちは　彷徨える未来
bokutachi wa samayoeru mirai
We are a future of dubious likelihood
窮屈な空に　ヒカリを探している
kyuukutsu na sora ni
We look to the oppressive sky
hikari wo sagashiteiru
in search of light
furueru te wa muryoku de
Our trembling hands are powerless
震える手は無力で
叫びはまだ遠くて
sakebi wa mata tookute
Our screams reach no one
たけど飛ぶことを恐れてはいられない
dakedo tobu koto wo
But we will never be afraid
osorete wa irarenai
of flying
永遠じゃなくても　完璧じゃなくても
eien ja nakutemo
We don't need eternity
kanpeki ja nakutemo
We don't need perfection
背中合わせの世界を　真っ直ぐ生きてゆく
senaka-awase no sekai wo
We live in two related
massugu ikiteyuku
but wildly different worlds
何度傷ついても　何度間違えても
nando kizu tsuitemo
No matter the wounds we receive
nando machigaetemo
and the mistakes we make,
運命さえ飛び越えていこう
unmei sae tobikoete yukou
we will overcome fate
この宙の果てまで
kono sora no hate made
Until the skies above us end
創造を信じて
hajimari wo shinjite
we will believe in the genesis of a better life